你在干什么?
What are you doing?
尽力回忆那些蓝图
I'm trying to remember those blueprints,
被烫伤丢失的部分
what we lost to the burn.
没有那部分 我们将永远无法穿越精神病区下面的管道
Without them, we'll never be able to navigate those pipes beneath psych ward.
但我必须搞清楚 你是在哪里被烧伤的
Then I need to know where you got that burn. Right now.
否则 就等着关禁闭吧
Otherwise, your ass is going to solitary.
我倾注了所有心血
I put my blood into this...
能否详细解释一下?
How about you elaborate on that?
能否不要再问这些问题?
How about you stop with all the questions?
你的工作是保镖 仅此而已
You are a glorified bodyguard, that's it.
好 我拿到了
Okay, I got it.
把枪放下 你不是个杀人犯
Put it down. You're not a killer.
让开
Get out of the way.
要知道 他们给你这些药物是有原因的
You know, maybe they give you those things for a reason.
是啊 以一种无形的方式把我束缚
Yeah. To keep me in their invisible freaking handcuffs.
你好 室友 你说得没错
Hello, roomie. You were right about my tattoo.
确实是通道
It is a path...
我要你回忆你看到它时候的样子
And I need you to remember when you saw it, Haywire.
你是谁?
Who are you?
斯科菲尔德 迈克尔·斯科菲尔德
Scofield. Michael Scofield.
毫无印象
Doesn't ring a bell.
我们先前在普通监区40号牢房见过的
We met a while ago in Gen pop. Cell 40.
-什么是区?  -普通监区
-Gen pop?  -General population.
贝利克警官安排你和我住一个房间
Officer Bellick assigned you to my cell.
我有纹身 你把它画下来了
I have a tattoo, you drew it.
海威尔 你对我一点印象都没了?
Haywire, do I look even vaguely familiar to you?
你是那个偷我牙膏的家伙?
Are you the guy who stole my toothpaste?
是的 是的 我偷了你的牙膏
Yes, yes. I stole your toothpaste.
这么说你记起来了
So you do remember.
吃糖了
Candy man.
帕托塞克先生
Mr. Patoshik.
-斯科菲尔德先生  -不用了 谢谢
-Mr. Scofield.  -No, thank you.
服药是强制性的
Medication is mandatory.
只是一种很温和的镇定剂 唐克雷蒂医生开的 来吧
It's just a mild sedative prescribed by Dr. Tancredi. Come on.
那我就直接跟她谈 我现在感觉好多了
Then I'll talk to her directly. I'm feeling better.
哦 真的吗? 很好 好 现在吃药
Oh, really? That's great. Now take the pill.
吃吧 味道还不错的
Take them. They're good.
我不要 谢谢
I'm fine. Thank you.
卡特 你能过来一下吗?!
Carter, could you come here a sec?
斯科菲尔德被送到精神病区了?
Scofield went J-Cat?
当然 我也看到了
Sure did. I saw it coming, too.
我第一眼看见他的时候就知道 他会精神崩溃的
I knew he was gonna crack first time I saw him.
就是说他不会再回这儿了
So he's not coming back here?
我比较怀疑 他们都已经把他单独禁闭了
Doubt it. They had him in the whack shack.
-苏克雷怎么说?  -他也被关单独禁闭 怎么了?
-What about Sucre?  -He's in ad seg. Why?
房间居中 楼层居中 属于上等牢房
Middle cell, middle tier, prime piece of real estate.
知道我在想什么吗?
You thinking what I'm thinking?
或许
Maybe.
我们可以把它作为暂住单间拍卖掉
We promise to keep it a single for a couple of months, auction it off.
那就做吧
Make it happen.
我不需要药物
I don't need medication.
吞下去 否则从你的"后门"塞进去
Swallow it, or it's going in the rear door.
全吞下去了?
All gone?
不错
Nice.
你说得很对 海威尔 我确实偷了你的牙膏
You were right, Haywire. I did steal your toothpaste,
你曾凭借记忆临摹了我的纹身 我要你再画一次
and you drew that tattoo from memory, and I need you to do it again.
居中的房间 冬暖夏凉
Middle cell, cool in the summer, warm in the winter.
-你出价多少?  -你有多少?
-How much you asking?  -How much you got?
200块 成交吗?
$200. We got a deal?
成交
Deal.
好 你现在可以出去了 我给你办转移手续
Now get your ass out of here and I'll put in the transfer.
嘿 伙计 马桶漏水的
Hey, man, the toilet's leaking.
看 有漏水
Look, it's dripping.
我会叫人来修的 24小时内换新
I'll put in a work order. It'll be replaced in 24 hours.
说好了 头儿
You got it, boss.
听说你在搞点房地产小生意
I heard you was moving some real estate.
已经成交了
Already been moved.
-斯科菲尔德的牢房?  -不再是他的了
-Ain't that Scofield's cell?  -Not anymore.
40号关上!
Close on 40!
这是你女儿?
Is that your daughter?
她出生的时候 我老婆给了我这照片
My wife gave me this when she was born.
失去老婆的生活已经够糟糕了
Outliving your wife is bad enough.
失去女儿
Outliving your daughter...
不应该有人去遭受这种折磨
No man should have to endure that.
她还能活多久?
How long does she have?
医院说是一周 顶不过两周
Hospital says a week, maybe two.
出问题了
We got us a problem.
"麻鸡"要搬到斯科菲尔德的房里去了 这还没完
Mojo's moving into Scofield's cell, and that ain't all.
他还抱怨马桶漏水 所以加里下了维修通知单
He's bitching about the toilet, so Geary's putting in a work order.
-一旦移动马桶...  -就会发现那个洞
-They move that toilet...  -They find the hole.
-我们就全完了  -麻鸡出价多少?
-We are all screwed.  -How much Mojo promise?
200块
$200.
呵 傻子 差点被你吓着了
Oh, Gomer, now you see, you had me scared there for a second.
-听说你有个新牢房  -已经没有了
-I hear you got a cell.  -Not anymore.
如果你够聪明的话 最好不要说出去
And if you were smart, you'd keep quiet about that.
嘿 听着 我付你双倍的钱
Hey, look, I'll double what you're getting.
他付了我$250
I'm getting $250.
$500? 没问题
$500? Ain't a problem.
我不是在这说香烟或者点心什么的
I ain't talking cigarettes and extra chow line desserts here.
我要的是印有那些白鬼头像的绿颜色大钞票
I'm talking green paper with dead white guys on it.
我说了 不成问题
I said it ain't a problem.
走
Come on.
-去哪?  -给你个惊喜
-Where?  -It's a surprise.
我没穿纸尿布
I don't wear a diaper.
我从没说过你穿了
I never said you did.
那你想干什么?
Then what are you doing?
你牙齿里有东西
You got something in your teeth.
-什么?  -哦 好 就在那儿
-What?  -Oh, yeah. Right there.
就在背面
It's right there in the back.
来吧
Come on.
你干吗这么做?
Why are you doing this?
我是在帮你
I am helping you.
记得你曾把这些药片称为什么吗?
Remember what you used to call those little pills?
"无形的手铐"
"Invisible handcuffs."
你精神上的束缚
Handcuffs on your mind.
你讨厌这个 记得吗?
You hate them, remember?
有电话
You got a phone call.
-是谁?  -你儿子. 有急事
-Who is it?  -Your son. It's an emergency.
哦 L.J. 你在想什么 孩子?
Oh, LJ, what were you thinking, kid?
我豁出去了 他妈的不管了
I don't care what happens to me anymore, okay?
他们赢了 他们总是赢
They won. They'll always win.
我只想拖一个下水
I just wanted to take one of them down with me.
让维罗妮卡听电话
Put Veronica back on.
-林肯?  -什么指控?
-Lincoln?  -What are the charges?
杀人未遂
Attempted murder.
他同时还将被指控 谋杀她的母亲和他的继父
He's also being arraigned for the murder of his mother and his stepfather.
我猜保释是不太可能了?
I guess bail is out of the question?
是的
Exactly.
你还能做些什么吗?
Anything you can do?
此刻 唯一的希望是让他作为 未成年犯受审
Right now, his only shot is if we can get him tried as a minor.
但是他必须表现出一些悔意
But he needs to show some remorse.
我要向法庭表明 他只是个受到过度惊吓的孩子
I need to sell to the court that he was just a scared kid.
但他现在头脑发热 根本不听我的话
But where his head's at right now, he won't listen to me.
他会听我的 我得见他
He'll listen to me. I need to see him.
林肯 不可能的
Lincoln, there's no way.
如果他被作为成人指控 很可能也会像我一样被判死刑
He gets tried as an adult, he may as well sit in my lap in the chair.
-你必须得做点什么 维罗妮卡  -好吧 我向纠正部门申请试试
-You got to do something, Veronica.  -Okay. Look, I'll petition the DOC,
但允许你出去见他的可能性 几乎微乎其微
but it's a million-to-one shot they're gonna let you out to see him.
好吧
All right.
嘿 伙计
Yo, Trumpets.
我要你尽快收回所有的欠款 行吗?
You all gotta round up all outstanding debts that are due ASAP, all right?
-现在?  -跟往常一样 好吗?
-Do it right now?  -Like yesterday, all right?
-我马上搞定  -好
-I'll put it out there.  -Good.
你疯了?
Are you insane?
没你的事了 做保镖的
You are done, bodyguard.
林肯的儿子 一个16岁的吸毒小孩
Lincoln's son, a 16-year-old pothead,
轻易的查到了你的住址 并打伤了你
managed to track you down and shoot you.
你现在是他的案子的目击证人了
You are now a witness in his criminal investigation.
我照样可以干我的活
I can still do my job.
你无论如何都不能 再管布伦斯的案子了
You are not to make a move on Burrows under any circumstance.
一切由我们来管
We make that call.
知道吗 特里克茜?
You know what, trixie?
其实我们还有更重要的任务安排要做
There are actually higher agendas here.
是的 说的没错 但都没你参加的份儿了
Yes, there are, and they don't belong to you.
保罗·凯勒曼不再为特勤部门工作
Paul Kellerman no longer works for the Secret Service.
从现在开始 你就是以前那个欧文·克雷维克了
You're just good old Owen Kravecki from now on.
我说得明白吗?
Have I made myself clear?
嘿
Hey.
我要你集中精力
I need you to focus.
我需要你回忆起你画的东西
I need you to remember what you drew.
海威尔 集体活动了
Haywire. Time for group.
来吧 伙计 我们走
Come on, buddy. Let's go.
走吧
There we go.
是条通道
It's a path.
对 就是一条通道
Yes. It is a path.
我们走
Let's go.
什么事 伙计?
So, what's up, man?
事情是这样 你什么都拿不到了
Here's the thing. You got nothing coming.
你那些出色的手下 现在都是我的了
All your outstanding markers, they're mine now.
是这样吗?
Is that so?
觉得有问题的话 跟你那些新混混哭去吧
You got a problem with it, go cry to your new crew,
帝博格和那些小白脸
T-Bag and the white boys.
哦... 好 原来是关于这个
Okay, so that's what this is all about.
这是关于站稳你自己
This is about staying true to your own.
知道吗 伙计?
Well, you know what, man?
只要我想 我可以一边和3K党的老大们喝喝茶
I can have tea with the grand wizard of the KKK if I want,
一边 钱照样拿 你明白吗 臭小子?
and I still get my money. You got that, little boy?
不 我们不明白
No. We don't got that.
看在你以前的份上 我就让你走着离开这儿
Now, out of respect for what you once were, I'm gonna let you walk away.
你说得对
You were right.
药物使得我记不起那条通道
The pills don't let me see the pathway.
那是一条通向地狱的路
That's a pathway to hell.
不 不是 恰恰相反
No, it's not. It's just the opposite.
我记起来了
I remember.
看来"非洲银行"提不出钱来了
Looks like the Bank of Africa wasn't allowing any withdrawals.
听着 我们得另找法子搞钱
Look, we are gonna have to find another way to get that money, okay?
嗯 我想这对我们这位 在坐的朋友来说
Well, then I reckon it ain't too much of a problem
搞到钱不是太难啊 对吗 D.B?
for our friend here to rummage up, ain't that so, D.B.?
首先 我不是D.B库珀 其次 今天没有探监
A, I'm not D.B. Cooper, and, B, there's no visitation today.
也就是说 没人可以从外面给我们捎钱
Which means that none of us can get any money from the outside world.
看来只有一条路可走了
I guess that only leaves us with one real option.
厨房游戏
The kitchen game.
赌博? 这就你所谓的办法?
Gambling? And that's your solution?
小子 相信我
Son, trust me.
我玩牌的时候 那不叫赌博
When I play cards, it ain't gambling.
这个国家也许只有5个人
There's maybe five people in this country that
可以像我一样玩转堵牌
can do what I do with a deck of cards.
为什么你现在才说?
So why are you just bringing this up now?
因为如果被上帝看到我在如此玩牌
'Cause if Jesus, over there,
这么说吧 我会被上帝搞死
catches you sleeving aces in the kitchen game,
当然 你至少要有50美金才能坐下玩
Of course, you need 50 bucks just for the sit-in,
可我们一分都没有
and since we don't have any money,
我不得不说 这下我们是真陷入困境了
I'd say we're in a catch-doubley-deuce.
坐这儿
You sit right here.
拿好这个
Take this.
还有这个
And this.
哦 不... 一块没了
Oh, no. It's gone.
所以我才要你补好它
That's why I need you to fix it.
所以我才要你回忆起它原来是什么样子
That's why I need you to remember what was there before.
哦 太糟糕了 你不能把路给弄断了
Oh, this is bad. You can't break a path.
不然就找不到出路了
Then it doesn't lead anywhere.
说得没错
That's right.
所以我才要你回忆起我把它弄糟之前是什么样子
That's why I need you to remember what was there before it was broken.
我记得
I remember.
我记得有个鬼怪的图
I remember the demons.
等等 也许是个朝圣者的头像
Wait, no, maybe they were pilgrims.
他们指着路的方向 好像是在说:"往这边走 往这边走"
They were pointing to the way, and they were saying, "This is the way, this is the way."
我不明白
I can't see it.
我看的到图 但我搞不明白
I can see it, but I can't see it.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
嘿!
Hey!
我要你帮我给苏克雷捎个信
I need you to give Sucre a message.
告诉他我没事儿 我在尽量填补空白
Tell him I'm okay, and that I'm trying to fill in the blanks.
他会知道我的意思
He'll know what that means.
你在尽量填补空白?
You're trying to fill in the blanks?
照着做就是了.拜托了
Just do it. Please.
这下我该怎么办?
What the hell am I gonna do now?
就我所知 你在13号牢房已经呆到现在了
You've been down in 13 as long as I can remember.
为什么突然有兴趣换地方?
Why the sudden interest in moving?
像这样的二层牢房并不多得
Second-story units like this don't come on the market too much.
我想 年纪都已经这么大了
I figure since I'm getting on in age,
是该享享清福了
maybe it's time I retired in comfort.
打开40号牢房
Open on 40!
动作快点
Make it quick.
嘿... 鲍勃·维拉 这只是个牢房而已
Hey, Bob Vila, it's a cell.
别磨蹭时间 快做出决定
Quit kicking the tires and make a decision.
我付你100块 换这个房间
I'll give you 100 bucks for it.
别浪费我的时间了 还是走吧
You wasted my time. Get the hell out of here.
抱歉 老大 我还以为我出价不错
Sorry, boss. I thought it was a good bid.
40号关上
Close on 40!
好啊 本杰明(钞票上的总统头像)
Hello, Benjamin.
我看看 是在19..72年制造
Now, let me see, minted in 19 and 72.
这是你的本钱 剩下的只能靠你了
That's your buy-in. The rest is up to you.
可恶的...
Hot damn.
继续走 啄木鸟
Keep walking, peckerwood.
搞到本钱了
Got the buy-in for the card game.
那就去搞剩下的部分吧
Go get our money, boy.
不幸的是 这次行动你必须做我的搭档
Unfortunately, you and I are gonna have to be partners in this endeavor.
哦 不 不行
Oh, hell, no.
我不会玩牌 我只会玩骰子
I don't play cards, I'm a dice man.
听着 你只需这么做
Look, all you need to know is this,
每次我发牌时 你都要赌大的 不许不要
every time I deal, you bet big and never fold.
如果每次我发牌 且还都是我赢的话
See, if I'm winning every time I deal,
我最后的结局会是和 哥伦比亚绳索长眠 懂我意思吗?
I end up with a Colombian necktie. You know what I'm saying?
但如果每次都是你赢钱
But if you're the one raking in all the cash,
他们就不会想到 其实我和你是一伙的
well, I seriously doubt anyone would ever think you and I are working together.
打扰一下 哪里都找不到这手机的充电器
Excuse me. I've been all over town. I can't find a charger for this.
-让我查查看  -谢谢
-Well, let me check.  -Thanks.
别来无恙啊 萨维恩?
How you doing, Savrinn?
你那女孩呢?
Where's your girl?
她在做她的事 行吗?
She's doing her job, all right?
向法院写申请书
Filing a petition down at the courts.
她... 她将于一个小时后回到我的住所
She'll be at my place in about an hour.
看 很容易吧
See, that was easy.
我本不必向你追要那条信息的
I shouldn't have to chase you down to get that information.
你为什么就不能退后一步?
Why don't you just take a step back?
你为什么不想想你在跟谁讲话 我是为谁工作的?
And why don't you remember who you're talking to, who I work for?
你给我认真盯着维罗妮卡·多诺万
You need to keep an eye on Veronica Donovan.
不是偶尔盯着 是一直给我盯着
Not some of the time, all of the time.
因为马上事态就会偏向我们这一边了
'Cause pretty soon, we're gonna call in our favor,
除非你想回到我们的老交易上去
unless you want to go back on our deal.
-我懂了  -很好
-No.  -Good.
保持联系
Be in touch.
海威尔
Haywire.
海威尔... 你吃药了吗?
Haywire, did you take your meds?
来
Well, come on.
你牙缝里又有东西了
You got something in your teeth again.
要别人回忆往事可以 但自己也得小心点儿 迈克尔
You should be careful when you tell people to remember things, Michael.
因为我记起了所有的事情
Because I remember everything now.
包括你是怎么陷害我的!
I remember how you set me up!
以及你如何撞破你的头...
How you smashed your own head
害得我被遣送到这里
and had me sent back here.
我同时...
I also
也记起了这个
remember this.
通道
The pathway.
你的地图
Your map.
你的越狱
Your escape.
-给我  -别.别
-Give me that.  -Don't. Don't.
现在 你是要我把这撕了...
Now, do I tear this up
...还是告诉我 何时 何地开始你的越狱行动?
or do you tell me exactly where and when you're doing this?
-从地下室开始  -好
-It starts in the basement.  -Okay.
这条线连接着煤房舱口和这边的管道系统
This line leads from the hatch in the coal room, to this pipe system here,
而那条线可以通到医务室
and that runs to the infirmary.
我们就是走这条线出去的
That's how we'll get out.
我得离开精神病区补全工作
I just need to get out of psych ward to set things up.
三天以后
But three days after I'm gone,
我再折回到地下室把你接出去
I'll come back up through the basement and get you out.
你只是说些我想听的话
You're just telling me what I want to hear.
不 我没有
No, I'm not.
我需要你帮我们离开这儿
I need you to let me get us out of here.
你需要相信我
I need you to trust me.
如果你再陷害我 我会杀了你
If you try to screw me over again I'll kill you.
嘿
Hey.
嘿 进展怎么样?
Hi. How did it go?
申请是挺容易的
Filing the petition was easy,
但能否通过 那就是另一回事儿了
getting it approved, that's a whole 'nother story.
-你找到充电器了?  -哦 是的
-You found the charger?  -Oh, yeah.
你怎么不把它装上去?
Why didn't you plug it in?
我只是在 嗯... 在想些其它的事情
I was just... Just thinking for a minute.
-想什么?  -没什么
-About what?  -Nothing.
-看来有事做了  -什么?
-We're in business.  -What is it?
他的整本电话簿都还在 总共322个号码
His entire phone book is still in here, 322 numbers.
没空位了 旁边等等
No open seats. Gotta wait.
西诺 押还是不押?
C-Note, crap or get off the pot.
我再想想
I'm thinking.
嘿 我们这不是在加拿大扑克邀请赛上玩
We ain't betting on CPT here, man.
你要么跟 要么滚开让位置
Either you gonna see his bet or you can go outside
去搞个囚犯大游行什么的 随你怎么搞
and Million Con March or whatever your people do.
不管你选择哪一种 快做决定就是了 伙计
Either way, get on with it, son.
我跟
I'm in.
三张Q娘么 你的呢?
Three bitches, bitches. What you holding?
你说呢
You tell me.
-满堂红  -满堂红?
-Full house.  -A full house?
这东西 墨西哥人应该非常熟悉 嗯 小子?
That's a concept a Mexican should be quite familiar with, eh, Jesus?
她说什么?
She said what?
她毫不含糊说
She said, in unequivocal terms,
布伦斯的事我不准再插手
that I was not to move on Burrows.
不管他们有何计划 和我们的肯定不一样
Whatever their agenda is with Burrows, it is not the same as ours.
他父亲的介入
This whole business with his father,
阻碍了我们最初计划的实施
it interferes with the one thing that we set out to do in the first place.
使我们对林肯·布伦斯的 一切行程安排落空
Put Lincoln Burrows in the ground.
只要他活着 你就只能等着认输 而不是公司
If he lives, you're the one that stands to lose, not the Company.
他们会再选个候选人
They get themselves another candidate,
而你却得承担所有损失
and you're the one that suffers the brunt of it.
也许是时候搞乱他们的棋盘了
Then maybe it's time we broke ranks.
如果我们那么做 他们将不再支持你的竞选 这你是知道的
We do that, they pull support for the campaign. You know that, don't you?
前提是... 如果被他们知道 保罗
That is, if they know, Paul.
嗯! 闻闻这些钱的味道 得来一对J或者更好 来三个就赢了
Smell that kitty. Jacks or better, Trips to win.
最后一手了 我今天已经输得不耐烦了
Last hand. I'm tired of losing all my money today.
-你那有多少?  -不知道 300上下
-How much you up?  -I don't know. $300.
-疼吗?  -什么?
-Does it hurt?  -What?
你屁股上的马蹄铁 (意指狗屎运)
The horseshoe up your ass.
今天运气很好 乒乓小子
Rather be lucky than good, ping-pong.
掉牌得弃牌
Misdeal. Bury the card.
伙计 我不在乎你有没看到我的牌
Man, I don't care if you all saw my card.
是啊 你当然不在乎
Yeah, I bet you don't.
弃牌吧 毛小子
Bury the card, young blood.
嘿 扫兴的家伙 这又不是我的错
Hey, chill, wrinkles. Ain't my fault saltine here got a sloppy deal.
啊 这种事情谁料得到
That there was just uncalled for.
好吧 听着 要不这么做
Now, all right. You know what? I'll tell you what.
我重新洗牌 你们也不要太孩子脾气了
I'm gonna deal another hand, you gonna be such a baby about it.
发错牌 就得弃牌 把牌发完
On a misdeal, you bury the card, finish out the hand.
这是规矩
House rules.
狱长
Warden.
有好消息 林肯
I have some good news for you, Linc.
不知怎的 你的律师的申请通过了
Somehow, your lawyer's petition went through.
纠正部门给你一个小时的时间来探望你儿子
The Department of Corrections is allowing you a one-hour visit with your son.
我还从没见过有这种优待 从没有
I've never seen one of these granted before, ever.
好律师
Good lawyers.
没律师能好到这种程度
No lawyer's that good.
我去安排行程
I'll make the travel arrangements,
不过这不是全国旅行
but this is not going to be a ride in the country.
你照样会被铐住 并有人全副武装看守
You're gonna be y-cuffed, and the men are gonna be heavily armed.
我不想造成任何不必要的麻烦
I don't want any problems.
不会的 我只想见见我的儿子
There won't be, I just want to see my son.
我全压了
I'll bet all I got.
82块钱
$82.
除非你运气好到连来几张A
You better have some aces shoved up there with that horseshoe,
否则我赢定了 跟还是不跟?
or that pot's mine. You in or out?
我跟
I'm in.
再加74块
And I raise you $74.
我说了我只有82
I said I only got $82 left.
我只能说你今天不走运
Well, then I guess you're out of luck.
你没听说过这是绅士游戏吗?
You never heard of a gentleman's game?
是的 我听说过 但这次不算
Yes, I have, but this ain't it.
要不要借点钱? 向你手下问问
You want to borrow some money? Ask your boys.
我今天是来这里赢钱的 老兄
But I'm in here to make money, bro.
你想要福利 最好投票给民主党
You want welfare, you'd better vote Democrat.
你知道怎么做对你有好处
If you know what's good for you,
最好在院子里离我远远的
you'll stay away from me in the yard.
你以为你比我更聪明?
You think you're smarter than me?
不!不!不 不 不!
No, no, no!
有条通道  不 有条通道!有条通道!
Okay, there's a pathway. No, there's a pathway! There's a pathway!
他想逃跑! 他想逃跑  这就是他的地图
Look, he's trying to escape! He's trying to escape. This is his map!
他陷害我!
He set me up!
电击!
Zap him!
他来了
There he is.
嘿 老大 你掉了点东西
Hey, boss. I think you dropped something, man.
这里有500 什么时候让我搬进去?
That's half a G-note. So when do I move in?
-不用搬  -什么?
-You don't.  -What?
拜托 头儿 我们说好的
Oh, come on, chief, now, we had a deal.
新价 涨到700了
Renegotiation, the price is $700 now.
这样太说不过去了 我已经给你500了
That ain't right. I just gave you $500.
你给我的只是定金
What you gave me was a down payment.
如果你支付不了余下部分 那么...
If you can't come up with the rest, well...
不 不 不 不 不! 等 等 等 稍等一会儿
No, no, no! Wait, wait, wait. Just hold on. One minute, all right?
这家伙想把我们淘空
Oh, man, he's trying to shake us down.
-我需要你的表  -没门儿
-I'm gonna need that watch.  -Not an option.
听着 你是宁可在这里看你女儿的照片呢
Look, would you rather be looking at a picture of your daughter
还是想出去并有机会抱她一下?
or holding her in your arms once you get outside?
听着 伙计 老头儿欠我些钱
Hey, look, man, Father Time owed me a few bones.
用这个作抵押了
He gave me this in trade.
现在多的都有了
That should be more than enough to cover it.
嗯 还不赖
Not bad.
问题是已经有人出价700要那个房间了 看来你被卡住了
Your problem is somebody already gave me $700 for the cell, so, you're S.O.L.
不! 嘿 等等! 等等! 等等!
No! No! Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa! Wait a minute, wait a minute, wait a minute. Look.
你想拿了我的钱就走人?
So you're just gonna take my money and walk?
是啊 写信去投诉我吧
Yeah, well, write to your congressman.
要命了!
Oh, come on!
来了
Hey.
恩 他们说你想跟我谈谈
Hi. They said you wanted to talk to me.
是的 是啊
Yeah, yeah.
好吧
Okay.
好
Good.
请坐
Please.
谢谢
Thanks.
我给你做了个东西
I made you something.
是个烟灰缸
It's an ashtray.
嗯... 可我不抽烟
I don't smoke.
是 我知道 但他们只让我们做这个和珠宝
Yeah, I know. But they only let us make these and jewelry,
而且我觉得你不是那种喜欢带面条项链的人
and I didn't figure you for the macaroni necklace type.
真好! 嗯...
It's very sweet.
我们谈谈你的情况吧?
How about we talk about how you're doing?
我想 你和我都知道 我不应该呆这里
I think we both know I don't belong here.
我记不清那晚发生了什么事
I don't remember much about that night,
但被关单独禁闭的时候 一定是什么东西让我头脑发涨
but being locked up in ad seg, something must've snapped.
我想说的是 我已经干了很多的手工艺活
What I'm trying to say is, I think I've had enough of arts and crafts.
但那是由你决定的
But that's your call.
这里的医生确实是说 你表现还不错
And the doctors here do say that you've been acting fine.
问题是 如果你不告诉狱长是谁烫伤了你
The problem is that if you don't tell the Pope who burned you,
他还是会把你单独禁闭的
he's gonna lock you back up in ad seg.
几天以后 你可能又会被送回来
And after a couple days of that, you're gonna be right back here.
迈克尔 我很不愿看到在你身上发生的一切 以及你坐在这儿
Michael, I hate what happened to you, and I hate that you're here.
但你得让我帮你
But you have got to let me help you.
如果你想离开这个精神病区
If you want to get out of psych ward, and stay out,
你就得把事实告诉狱长
you've got to tell the Pope the truth about that burn.
换洗衣物了 朋友们
Out with the old, in with the new, cons.
你室友让我给你捎个信儿 哥
I got a message from your cellie, bro.
他说他没事儿 并努力填补空白
He says he's okay and he's trying to fill in the blanks.
他说他正在尝试 还是说已经填好了?
Did he say he's trying, or that he already got the blanks filled in?
我不知道 我没写下来
Yo, man, I don't know. I didn't write it down.
好吧 你告诉他 我已经把洞填平了
Okay. Now you gotta tell him that I filled in the hole.
好 好 我已经厌烦了你的秘密和口信儿
Yeah, yeah, I'm done with your little secrets and messages, bro.
我看到斯科菲尔德的背部了
I saw Scofield's back.
他背部被烫伤的部分 和警服的那一块是同一个位置
He's got a burn in the same spot as the burn in that guard's shirt.
我不知道你在干什么 但我已经有点头绪了
I don't know what you're doing but I have an idea, huh?
除非你告诉我发生了什么事 否则我不帮你了
And I'm through helping you until you tell me what's going on.
我不能告诉你 兄弟
I can't, bro.
那祝你好运吧
Then good luck in the hole, jefe.
不 不 不 不 不! 等 等
No, no, no! Wait, wait.
曼而彻
Manche.
谁在叫?
Who's that?
是林肯 兄弟
That's Linc, bro.
-判死刑的林肯?  -是的
-Linc the Sink?  -Yeah.
过来
Come here.
我想我们可以解决点问题
I think we can work something out.
我想说的是 在我离开这儿之前 加里会付出代价的 相信我
All I can say is, before I get out of here, Geary will pay. Believe that.
如果维修部换新了斯科菲尔德的马桶 谁都走不了
No one's getting out of here if maintenance goes to replacing Scofield's toilet.
我有办法帮你们 解决斯科菲尔德的问题
I got a way to help you with your Scofield problem.
你说什么 瘦竹竿?
What'd you say, slim?
我说我有办法帮你们...
I said I got a way to help you with...
谁告诉你我们有问题?
Who the hell said we had a problem?
冷静点 老兄 放轻松
It's cool, man. Relax.
林肯和苏克雷把什么都告诉我了
Lincoln and Sucre told me everything.
他们告诉你什么了?
What in the hell did they tell you?
他们到底告诉你什么了?
Exactly, what did they tell you?
什么都说了 他们说 我可以和你们一起
Everything. They said I can come with you, you know,
提前假释 如果我能帮你们 把迈克尔弄出精神病区的话
on early parole, if I can help get the Fish out of psych.
我们算什么 火车吗? 你以为谁都能上我们的火车?
What are we, the A train? Everyone gets to ride with us?
在我给你一拳之前 先给我滚蛋?
Why don't you take a walk, before I give you a smack?
你有其它的好办法吗?
You got another solution to our situation?
我可不这么认为
I didn't think so.
我 我堂哥还有林肯... 想了个法子
Me and my cuz and Lincoln came up with something.
行得通... 但有一定风险
Now, it can work, but it's risky.
准备好离开这鱼缸了吗 小鱼儿?
You ready to get out of this aquarium, Fish?
你必须保证我没事
Assure me I'll be protected.
迈克尔 你已经够了解我了 你知道我会怎么做
Michael, you know me well enough by now. Such assurances are not necessary.
恕我直言 狱长
With all due respect, Warden,
如果当初安全措施够好的话 那样的事就不会发生了
if I had been protected in the first place, none of this would have happened.
名字
A name.
-加里  -加里?
-Geary.  -Geary?
他想尽办法从我们这捞钱 不择手段
He shakes cons down for money, anything he can get his hands on.
他知道我上过大学 所以他理所当然认为我...
He knew I went to college, so he must've...
他一定认为我很有钱
He must've thought I was rich or something.
总之 当 嗯...
Anyway,
我付不出钱的时候 他用一只手把我摁住
when I couldn't pay up, he held me down with one arm,
用另一只手烫我
and burned me with the other.
我不知道他用什么烫的 但...
but it was hot as hell. but
真的是烫的要命
it was hot as hell.
真是让人诧异啊 又接不通
What a surprise. Disconnected.
250个商用电话 72个家用电话 遍布50个州...
Two-hundred and fifty businesses, 72 residences, covering all 50 states.
伦敦 马提尼克岛 雅加达 达喀尔...
London, Martinique, Jakarta, Dakar.
所有号码都已经停用
All the numbers out of service.
魁恩一失踪 几天内他们就把数据全部销毁了
As soon as Quinn disappeared, they must've erased the paper trail within days.
还有什么他们办不到的?
Is there anything they can't do?
我在华盛顿的朋友
My P.I. Buddy in DC.
我把这个都寄过去
What if I send him all this,
看他能不能在这些号码之间找到某种联系?
see if he can make a connection between the numbers?
我会告诉他尽快
I'll tell him I need it ASAP.
谢谢
Thank you.
没什么大不了的 我会让他通宵处理这些材料
Oh, it's no big deal. I'll just overnight him all this stuff.
不是 是为了所有你做的事
No. For everything.
和我在一起 共同努力
For hanging in there, keeping me going.
谢谢
Thank you.
当然
Sure.
年薪400万的家伙
Guy with a six ERA, signs for four mil a year.
工作干得遭透了 却还能加薪
Sucks at his job, he still gets a raise.
你也干得很遭 你也向狱长要求加薪啊
You suck at your job. You should ask the Pope for a raise.
很有意思
Very funny.
狱长 什么风把你吹来了?
Warden, what brings you to our little clubhouse?
嘿 是什么...?
Hey, what gives?
嘿 这是我爸给我的
Hey, that was a gift from my old man.
你什么时候改姓"查尔斯"而你爸爸叫"安"了?
Since when is your name Charles and your dad's name Ann?
我是被冤枉的 我什么也没干!
This is a railroad. I didn't do nothing!
别像看罪犯那样看着我 你也不是个好东西
Don't look at me like I'm some con. You're as crooked as scoliosis.
我没有被抓住
I don't get caught.
我们到了以后
When we get there,
我会卸下你的手铐 让你稍微活动一下
I'll take you out of the y-cuffs and put you in a four-piece.
明白了吗?
Got it?
明白了 头儿
Got it, boss.
你乖一点 我也不会拿你怎么着 明白吗?
You play nice, I play nice. Understand?
明白了
Got it.
她在这儿 我正看着她
She's here. I've got her.
斯科菲尔德 重新回到普通监区
Scofield for re-admission to Gen pop.
-欢迎回家  -谢谢
-Welcome home.  -Thanks.
从没想过回牢房会让我这么开心
Never thought I'd be so glad to be back in my cell.
嗯 狱长要我把这个交给你
Pope wanted me to give you this.
你看什么呢
What the hell are you staring at, anyway?
什么都看
Everything.